Saïd Ziani

Having a track record of continually improving the way software works, I'm trying always to apply my technical know-how to build and improve large-scale, distributed, modern (not only) and high-volume systems. I like to understand complex architectures, to be involved in solving challenging technical problems and become expert on the components that I build or enhance.



saidziani.pro@gmail.com

+31 6 19988210 (WhatsApp)

Amsterdam, Netherlands

github.com/saidziani (7)

Work experience

Amsterdam, NL 08/2022 - present

Software Engineer - Backend

PVH Corp, Stitch

- Participate in a development of a robust upgrade version of the company's software applications DesignHub and RenderFarm - resulting in improved user experience and a revenue increase.
- Work closely with 3D designers and experts to understand specific needs and translate them into easy-tounderstand feature requests.
- Think, design and develop API endpoints that expose performant functionalities using Django and AWS.
- Improve the applications monitoring, logging and alerting systems.
- Part of the DoD rotation (Firebrigade) to ensure services reliability 24/7.
- Resolve escalated bugs and optimize the overall performance, reliability, and efficiency.

Technologies: Python3.x, Django (DRF), Celery, S3, PostgreSQL, Docker, EC2.

05/2021 - 08/2022

Software Engineer - Data Acquisition data.ai, formerly AppAnnie

- Analyze the technical feasibility of data collection product features and help guide development.
- Design and implement performant, scalable, and distributed web services and scraping pipelines.
- Own parts of the systems that gets data from web/mobile applications stores.
- Work closely with Reverse Engineers to understand APIs behaviors.
- Part of the DoD rotation to ensure services reliability 24/7.
- Designed, implemented and deployed a scaling scraping pipeline for GooglePlay Ratings from one single page (global rating) to 64 localized country rating.
- Extended the apps coverage for GooglePlay App details from 1.2M to 6.6M apps without increasing the costs spent on computation/storage.

Technologies: Python2.7/3.x, Bash, Scrapy, Celery, API Gateway, Lambdas, S3, SQS, SNS, CloudWatch, RDS, Docker, Jenkins.

04/2019 - 05/2021 Nijmegen, NL

Software Engineer - Data Visualisation

Censo

- Work with an agile team to consistently deliver and maintain new features and functionalities
- . Understand the Energy field business and the business impact of the code.
- Ensured high quality data collection and maintaining the integrity of the data. Communicate technical decisions through design docs, tech talks, and wikis.
- Helping to improve our build processes to make deployment and iteration easier and faster.
- Mentor junior engineers via pairing, design review, and code review.

Technologies: Python3, Django, GraphQl, Swagger, SonarCloud, PostgreSQL, JS, VueJS, Apollo.

06/2018 - 04/2019 Algiers, DZ

Software Engineer - Natural Language Processing Djezzy OTA

- Contribute in developing a platform for pre-processing and analyzing social media fans comments.
- Implement REST API which expose NLP model results.
- Participate in creating, testing and deploying Djezzy's mobile/web app.
- Documented all the workflow with design details and flowchart
- Provided extended support for Production releases and assisted in validating the releases. Responsible for code reviews, sprint planning and served as a scrum master.

Technologies: Python, Flask, Sentiment Analysis, NLP, Heroku, Data scraping.

02/2018 - 06/2018 Algiers, DZ

Graduated Data Scientist

Big-Mama

- Data Cleansing and preprocessing for different data science problems (Real Time Bidding).
- Implement Machine/Deep Learning Algorithms for Healthcare project.

Technologies: Python, TensorFlow, Pandas, Scala, Kafka, Akka Stream, MongoDB.

11/2017 - 06/2018 Algiers, DZ

Intern, Master's Graduation Project TALAA, Computer Science Dprt./USTHB

- Trained NLP ML models for Text Classification and an Algorithm for Automatic Text Summarization.
- Created a recommendation system to suggest news articles to the users.
- Building Corpus for News Article classification (Ar/En).
- . Developed a mobile app and REST api to expose and consume all previous modules.

Technologies: Python, ScikitLearn, Flask, AWS S3, React-Native, JavaScript, JSX, CSS3, MongoDB.

06/2017 - 11/2017 Algiers, DZ

Junior Web Developer

Hive-Digit

- . Worked mainly on B2B e-Commerce platform and participate in the software architecture.
- Extensively write PHP backend code, unit testing and security audits.

Technologies: PHP, Yii2, JavaScript, JQuery, AJAX, HTML5, CSS3, REST API.

09/2015 - 06/2016 Algiers, DZ

Intern, Software Developer COSIDER Canalisations

Updated an existing supply process information system.

Developed an ERP module, integrated with Data visualization Dashboard.

Technologies: PHP, JavaScript, JQuery, AJAX, HTML5, CSS3, MySQL.

Skills & competences

Programming Language

Python 2.x/3.x, JavaScript, TypeScript, Bash Scripting

Frameworks, Libraries

Django, FastAPI, Flask, Graphene, GraphQI, REST

Cloud and Serverless (AWS)

API Gateway, Lambdas, SQS, CloudWatch, Step Functions, SNS, DynamoDB, AWS CDK, SAM CLI...

Databases & Storage

AWS (RDS, S3, DynamoDB), RDBMS (PostgreSQL, MySQL)

Frontend

Utrecht, NL

VueJS, ReactJS, Apollo, Ant-Design

Data Manipulation

Data Scraping, Data Cleansing, ETLs

Monitoring, Logging & Alerting

Grafana, AWS CloudWatch, Slack

Dev Tools

Git, Docker, AWS CLI, PagerDuty, Jenkins, SonarQube, Heroku, Linux

Education

09/2016 - 06/2018

Masters - Intelligent Computer Systems University of Science and Technology, Algiers

Machine Learning | Natural Language Processing | Data Mining | Information Retrieval | Knowledge representation and reasoning | Constraint programming | e-Commerce & Web services | Advanced Databases.

09/2013 - 06/2016

Bachelor - Computer Science

University of Science and Technology, Algiers

Mathematics | Algorithmics | Operational research | Computer architecture | Databases | Programming and Web development | Physics | Analog electronic.

Extracurricular

Colorado 02/2019

HackCU Episode V Hackathon University of Colorado Boulder, USA

10/2018 Amsterdam

VEON Global Digithon'18 Hackathon VEON Group

09/2018 Algiers

1st place winner Djezzy's Hackathon OTA Djezzy

05/2018 Abu Dhabi

1st place winner NYUAD Hackathon **New York University**

Algiers, Telemcen 05/2016 - 08/2017

CTF - Capture The Flag SIT CTF, Hack'tillS7our, MCTF

03/2017 Algiers

3rd place Hack!t National Hackathon Higher School of Computer Science

12/2016 Algiers

2nd place Algeria Web Awards Algiers department - AWA

05/2016 - 05/2018 Algiers

Git Trainer and GNU/Linux Install Party Organizer OpenMindsClub

Languages

Arabic(native)

French(bilingue)

English(advanced)